A Guide to the Social Movements Collection 1941-1984
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Social Movements Collection 1941-1984
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9430
The collection contains about 4,500 items (15 Hollinger boxes, ca. 6 linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The original Social Movements Collection was given to Special Collections by Mrs. Maveret Eleanor Staples Buenfil of the Reference Department of the University of Virginia Library on March 13, 1970, but new material continued to be added until 1981.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Committee for a Social Movements Collection (CSMC) was formed in the late sixties to search for and preserve the publications of the alternative press of America at the University of Virginia Library. The Committee decided to collect the writings of both the radical right and the radical left. Several activist groups flourished at the University of Virginia and Alderman Library employees (including Mavert Buenfil, Charles Finn, Steve Squire, and Kendon Stubbs) began an active effort to collect all kinds of ephemera relating to the protest movements, such as leaflets, newsletters, newspapers, press releases, etc. They also began to seek out other underground publications of extremist groups, by donation from members of the groups or subscription.
Scope and Content
This collection contains items collected from a diverse group of over 500 different social movement groups between 1941 and 1984. The types of materials include letters, mailings, posters, bumper stickers, pins, pamphlets, booklets, and reading lists. The collection contains about 4,500 items (15 Hollinger boxes, ca. 6 linear feet). The materials come from all over the world, but are mainly focused in the United States.
The largest issue addressed by this collection was the Vietnam War and the draft, but it also covered civil rights, the rise of feminism, student rights, the Black Panthers, desegregation at the state and local level, and the formation of libertarian and conservative groups. Much printed material has been transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging, in order to provide better access to serial titles and other printed material present in the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is organized alphabetically by group name, and chronologically within folders.
Contents List
- A.J. Muste Memorial Institute 1975 (Box-folder 1:1)
- A. Philip Randolph Institute 1969-1971 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Abbie Hoffman and Friends n.d. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Action Coordinating Committee to End Segregation in the Suburbs n.d. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Action for Forgotten Women 1975, n.d. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Action for Women in Chile n.d. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Ad Hoc Committee Against D.C. Crime Bill n.d. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Ad Hoc Committee for Christmas Week Vigil to Free All Political Prisoners [1969] (Box-folder 1:8)
- Ad Hoc Committee for Contraception and Abortion Information n.d. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Ad Hoc Committee for Justice n.d. (Box-folder 1:10)
- Ad Hoc Committee for Justice for Palestinians 1974 (Box-folder 1:11)
- Ad Hoc Committee on the Triple Revolution 1964 (Box-folder 1:12)
- Ad Hoc Committee to Support the Black Legal Defense Fund n.d. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Africa Fund 1973-1980 (Box-folder 1:14)
- Africa Today n.d. (Box-folder 1:15)
- Alabama Conference on Radical Social Change 1969 (Box-folder 1:16)
- All Points of View 1968-1973, n.d. (Box-folder 1:17)
- All Virginia Friends Conference 1969 (Box-folder 1:18)
- Donna Allen n.d. (Box-folder 1:19)
- Alliance Against Abortion n.d. (Box-folder 1:20)
- Alliance for the Preservation of Religious Liberty 1978 (Box-folder 1:21)
- Alliance of Southern Highlanders 1969 (Box-folder 1:22)
- Alternative Features Network n.d. (Box-folder 1:23)
- Alternative Press Centre 1971-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 1:24)
- Ambassador College (Box-folder 1:25)
- American Association for the Advancement of Science 1972 (Box-folder 1:26)
- American Atheist Center 1980, n.d. (Box-folder 1:27)
- The American Christian Party 1973, n.d. (Box-folder 1:28)
- American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU): Mailings 1969-1973, n.d. (Box-folder 1:29)
- American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU): Pamphlets-Amnesty 1973, n.d. (Box-folder 1:30)
- American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU): Pamphlets-Education and Schools 1964-1970 (Box-folder 1:31)
- American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU): Pamphlets-Literature Lists and General Information 1966-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 1:32)
- American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU): Pamphlets-miscellaneous 1964-1972, n.d. (Box-folder 1:33)
- American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU): Pamphlets-Nixon, Vietnam, and Dissent 1963-1973, n.d. (Box-folder 1:34)
- American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU): Pamphlets-Surveillance 1965-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 1:35)
- American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU): Policy Guide and Biennial Report 1970 (Box-folder 1:36)
- American Committee on Africa 1967 (Box-folder 1:37)
- American Federation of State, Country, and Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO n.d. (Box-folder 1:38)
- American Freedom Association 1968-1974 (Box-folder 1:39)
- American Freedom from Hunger Foundation n.d. (Box-folder 1:40)
- American Friends Service Committee (AFSC): Correspondence and Memos 1964-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 2:1)
- American Friends Service Committee (AFSC): Mailings and Posters 1967-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 2:2)
- American Friends Service Committee (AFSC): Pamphlets and Information-Armed Forces and the Draft 1959-1975 (Box-folder 2:3)
- American Friends Service Committee (AFSC): Pamphlets and Information-Community Relations and Housing 1964-1966, n.d. (Box-folder 2:4)
- American Friends Service Committee (AFSC): Pamphlets and Information-Miscellaneous 1960-1973, n.d. (Box-folder 2:5)
- American Friends Service Committee (AFSC): Pamphlets and Information-Organization information 1967-1970, n.d. (Box-folder 2:6)
- American Friends Service Committee (AFSC): Pamphlets and Information-Peace 1959-1966, n.d. (Box-folder 2:7)
- American Friends Service Committee (AFSC): Pamphlets and Information-Vietnam 1964-1973, n.d. (Box-folder 2:8)
- American Indian Mission 1971 (Box-folder 2:9)
- American Indian Treaty Council Information Center 1974 (Box-folder 2:10)
- American Indian Movement 1974 (Box-folder 2:11)
- American Institute for Marxist Studies [1970-1973], n.d. (Box-folder 2:12)
- American Jewish Alternatives to Zionism 1979 (Box-folder 2:13)
- American Jewish Congress or Near East Report 1973 (Box-folder 2:14)
- American-Korean Friendship and Information 1971-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 1:15)
- American Legion: Firing Line 1971 (Box-folder 2:16)
- American Party-Smitz Anderson 1972 (Box-folder 2:17)
- American Revolutionary Media (ARM) n.d. (Box-folder 2:18)
- America's Future 1972-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 2:19)
- Amnesty International, USA [1967] (Box-folder 2:20)
- AMPO [The US-Japan Mutual Security Treaty] n.d. (Box-folder 3:1)
- The Anglo-Saxon Christian Crusade, Inc. n.d. (Box-folder 3:2)
- Angola Committee in Amsterdam n.d. (Box-folder 3:3)
- Anti-Ballistic Missile System 1968-1969, n.d. (Box-folder 3:4)
- Attorney General 1958 (Box-folder 3:5)
- Bakhaus-Efficacy n.d. (Box-folder 3:6)
- Black GI's Alliance [1970] (Box-folder 3:7)
- The Black Mountain Press 1965-1973 (Box-folder 3:8)
- Black Workers Congress 1971-1974 (Box-folder 3:9)
- Black World Foundation n.d. (Box-folder 3:10)
- Bob Anthony n.d. (Box-folder 3:11)
- Black Panther Party 1967-1972, n.d. (Box-folder 3:12)
- Bonus March Coalition 1974 (Box-folder 3:13)
- Boycott Gulf Campaign [1974] (Box-folder 3:14)
- Brazilian Information Front 1969-1970, n.d. (Box-folder 3:15)
- Bread and Wine Commune n.d. (Box-folder 3:16)
- Bread for the World n.d. (Box-folder 3:17)
- Bread not Bombs 1973, n.d. (Box-folder 3:18)
- BREIRA: A Project of Concern in Diaspora-Israel Relations 1974-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 3:19)
- British Withdrawal from Northern Ireland Campaign n.d. (Box-folder 3:20)
- California Migrant Ministry 1969 (Box-folder 3:21)
- La Causa 1969 (Box-folder 3:22)
- Chicago Anarchist Black Cross n.d. (Box-folder 3:23)
- The Children's Foundation [1970] (Box-folder 3:24)
- Chile Solidarity Committee 1973-1974 (Box-folder 3:25)
- Chilean Political Refuge Committee 1978 (Box-folder 3:26)
- Christian Anti-Communist Crusade 1980 (Box-folder 3:27)
- Christian Committee for the USS Liberty 1970 (Box-folder 3:28)
- Christian Crusade Weekly 1968-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 3:29)
- Christian Educational Association 1979 (Box-folder 3:30)
- Christian Information Committee n.d. (Box-folder 3:31)
- Christians for Life n.d. (Box-folder 3:32)
- Mary Christiansen 1966 (Box-folder 3:33)
- Christopher Street West [1971] (Box-folder 3:34)
- Circle Pines Center 1970 (Box-folder 3:35)
- Citizens Against Legalized Murder (CALM) 1971 (Box-folder 3:36)
- Citizens Committee for Constitutional Liberties 1969-1973 (Box-folder 3:37)
- Citizens for Cohen 1973-1984 (Box-folder 3:38)
- Citizens for Humphrey-Muskie [1968] (Box-folder 3:39)
- Citizens for Impeachment [1973-1974] (Box-folder 3:40)
- Citizen's Party 1980 (Box-folder 3:41)
- Clergy and Laymen Concerned 1967-1974 (Box-folder 3:42)
- Clergymen's Committee on China 1967-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 3:43)
- Closer to It 1974 (Box-folder 3:44)
- Coal Miner's Legal Defense Fund 1973-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 3:45)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women 1974 (Box-folder 3:46)
- Coalition for a New Foreign and Military Policy 1975-1979 (Box-folder 3:47)
- Allan Cole-Vietnam 1941-1954, n.d. (Box-folder 3:48)
- The Collector's Network 1969-1970 Aug. (Box-folder 4:1)
- The Collector's Network 1970 Sep.-1972 Feb. (Box-folder 4:2)
- The Collector's Network 1972 Feb.-1972 Oct. (Box-folder 4:3)
- The Collector's Network 1972 Oct.-1973 Aug. (Box-folder 4:4)
- The Collector's Network 1973 Oct.-1975 Mar. (Box-folder 4:5)
- The Collector's Network 1975 Mar.-1976 Jul. (Box-folder 4:6)
- Commission on Religion in Appalachia n.d. (Box-folder 5:1)
- Committee for a More Progressive Fredericksburg 1968 (Box-folder 5:2)
- Committee for Draft Resistance 1967 (Box-folder 5:3)
- Committee for Sexual Law Reform 1971 (Box-folder 5:4)
- Committee for the Twenty Seven n.d. (Box-folder 5:5)
- Committee for the Twelve 1972 (Box-folder 5:6)
- Committee for World Development and Disarmament 1963 (Box-folder 5:7)
- Committee of One Hundred 1966 (Box-folder 5:8)
- Committee of Returned Volunteers: Letters and Pamphlets: Miscellaneous 1966-1977, n.d. (Box-folder 5:9)
- Committee of Returned Volunteers: Letters and Pamphlets: Vietnam 1967-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 5:10)
- Committee of Returned Volunteers: reports: Guatemala Perspective 1968 (Box-folder 5:11)
- Committee of Returned Volunteers: reports: Peru and Thailand 1970, n.d. (Box-folder 5:12)
- Committee to Aid American War Objectors: Vancouver, British Columbia 1967 (Box-folder 5:13)
- Committee to Aid the National Liberation Front of South Vietnam n.d. (Box-folder 5:14)
- Committee to Defend Babak Zahraie n.d. (Box-folder 5:15)
- Committee to Defend [Carlos] Feliciano 1967-1973, n.d. (Box-folder 5:16)
- Committee to Defend the Panther Twenty-One 1970, n.d. (Box-folder 5:17)
- Committee to Defend the Right to Boycott n.d. (Box-folder 5:18)
- Committee to Free Eddie Sanchez 1975, n.d. (Box-folder 5:19)
- Committee to Free Morton Sobell n.d. (Box-folder 5:20)
- Committee to Free David Rice/Ed Poindexter 1970-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 5:21)
- Committee to Open the Archives and Examine the Evidence 1973 (Box-folder 5:22)
- Committee to Save Alternative Radio 1976 (Box-folder 5:23)
- Committee to Support Ann McCurry 1974 (Box-folder 5:24)
- Committee to Support the Republic of Guinea-Bissau 1974, n.d. (Box-folder 5:25)
- Committees of Correspondence 1969 (Box-folder 5:26)
- Common Cause 1971, n.d. (Box-folder 5:27)
- Common Sense-Fayetteville, North Carolina n.d. (Box-folder 5:28)
- Common Sense-Philadelphia Action Report n.d. (Box-folder 5:29)
- Communist Party, USA 1971-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 5:30)
- Community Attention, Inc. 1971 (Box-folder 5:31)
- Community for Non-Violent Action 1973 (Box-folder 5:32)
- Community Market 1969-1970 (Box-folder 5:33)
- Community Organization for Urban Progress 1970 (Box-folder 5:34)
- Community Publication Cooperative n.d. (Box-folder 5:35)
- Concerned Citizens n.d. (Box-folder 5:36)
- Concerned Sociologists-University of Kansas 1970 (Box-folder 5:37)
- Conference on Radical Vocations in the White Community [1967] (Box-folder 5:38)
- Conference on Textile Workers' Rights 1967 (Box-folder 5:39)
- Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) 1962-1970, n.d. (Box-folder 5:40)
- Congress of Women's Organizations in Virginia 1973-1974 (Box-folder 5:41)
- Connections: San Francisco, California 1970-1971 (Box-folder 6:1)
- The Conservative Caucus 1975 (Box-folder 6:2)
- The Conservative Party of New York State 1973, n.d. (Box-folder 6:3)
- The Conspiracy n.d. (Box-folder 6:4)
- Constitutional Enterprises, Inc. n.d. (Box-folder 6:5)
- Constructive Action Party of the City College of the City University of New York n.d. (Box-folder 6:6)
- Consumer Alliance Palo Alto 1971 (Box-folder 6:7)
- Consumers Against the War n.d. (Box-folder 6:8)
- Consumer Clearinghouse, Inc. 1971 (Box-folder 6:9)
- Consumer Rights Committee n.d. (Box-folder 6:10)
- The Continental Walk 1976 (Box-folder 6:11)
- Cooperation in Documentation and Communication n.d. (Box-folder 6:12)
- Co-operative Union of Canada 1962 (Box-folder 6:13)
- Cornell University: New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations 1965-1971 (Box-folder 6:14)
- Richard Coughlin 1968 (Box-folder 6:15)
- Council for a Department of Peace, Inc. n.d. (Box-folder 6:16)
- Council for a Livable World 1967-1974 (Box-folder 6:17)
- Council for Christian Social Action [1965-1978] (Box-folder 6:18)
- Council of Southern Mountains-Youth Commission 1969 (Box-folder 6:19)
- Council on Economic Priorities n.d. (Box-folder 6:20)
- Council on Religion and International Affairs 1969 (Box-folder 6:21)
- Counseling Service: Monterey, California n.d. (Box-folder 6:22)
- Curmudgeon Award 1973 (Box-folder 6:23)
- Hyland Davis 1970 (Box-folder 6:24)
- D.C. Gazette n.d. (Box-folder 6:25)
- D.C. Puerto Rican Solidarity Committee 1976 (Box-folder 6:26)
- Defenders of the American Constitution n.d. (Box-folder 6:27)
- The Defense Committee: Philadelphia and New York 1970-1971 (Box-folder 6:28)
- Democratic Campaign Headquarters: Charlottesville, Virginia 1968 (Box-folder 6:29)
- Department of State 1966-1968 (Box-folder 6:30)
- Duke University 1962-1968, n.d. (Box-folder 6:31)
- East Coast Ministry of Information n.d. (Box-folder 6:32)
- Ecology Action Educational Institute 1969-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 6:33)
- Educational Research Bureau: Roanoke, Virginia 1966-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 6:34)
- The Educator n.d. (Box-folder 6:35)
- The Effemist n.d. (Box-folder 6:36)
- Electric Warrior Free Press 1974 (Box-folder 6:37)
- Embassy of the Republic of South Vietnam in Cuba 1969-1971 (Box-folder 6:38)
- Emergency Committee for a National Mobilization Against Racism n.d. (Box-folder 6:39)
- Emergency Committee to Defend Latin-American Filmmakers 1975 (Box-folder 6:40)
- Emergency Conference Committee n.d. (Box-folder 6:41)
- Emergency Nationwide Moratorium 1972 (Box-folder 6:42)
- Environmental Defense Fund n.d. (Box-folder 6:43)
- End the Draft Campaign 1971 (Box-folder 6:44)
- Endraft 1971, n.d. (Box-folder 7:1)
- Environmental Teach-In n.d. (Box-folder 7:2)
- Episcopal Churchmen for South Africa 1976 (Box-folder 7:3)
- Episcopal Pacifist Fellowship n.d. (Box-folder 7:4)
- Episcopal Peace Fellowship 1966-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 7:5)
- Equal Employment Opportunity Commission 1964, n.d. (Box-folder 7:6)
- ERAmerica n.d. (Box-folder 7:7)
- Eritreans for Liberation in North America 1974 (Box-folder 7:8)
- Expo '67 1967 (Box-folder 7:9)
- Facilitator 1967-1968 (Box-folder 7:10)
- Fair Housing Committee: Charlottesville, Virginia n.d. (Box-folder 7:11)
- Families of Registers for Amnesty (FORA) 1973 (Box-folder 7:12)
- Family Trusts 1971 (Box-folder 7:13)
- Farah Strike 1972 (Box-folder 7:14)
- Farm Workers Action Committee n.d. (Box-folder 7:15)
- Federally Employed Women n.d. (Box-folder 7:16)
- Federation of American Scientists 1972-1974 (Box-folder 7:17)
- Federation of Southern Cooperatives n.d. (Box-folder 7:18)
- Fellowship Publications 1967, n.d. (Box-folder 7:19)
- The Feminist History Research Project n.d. (Box-folder 7:20)
- First Casualty Press 1972 (Box-folder 7:21)
- First National Cosmic Science Church n.d. (Box-folder 7:22)
- For Peace and Brotherhood 1971 (Box-folder 7:23)
- Foreign Policy Association, Inc. 1970 (Box-folder 7:24)
- Fort Hood Three Defense Committee n.d. (Box-folder 7:25)
- Foundation for Economic Education 1953-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 7:26)
- Founding Conference for a National Defense Organization Against Racism and Political Oppression 1973 (Box-folder 7:27)
- Frank Shuford Defense Committee 1975-1976 (Box-folder 7:28)
- H. Bruce Franklin and the University of Colorado 1974, n.d. (Box-folder 7:29)
- Fredericksburg Area Ministerial Association 1968 (Box-folder 7:30)
- The Free College at Williamsburg n.d. (Box-folder 7:31)
- Free People n.d. (Box-folder 7:32)
- Free School Press 1966-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 7:33)
- Free University of New England (FUNE) n.d. (Box-folder 7:34)
- Free University of New York n.d. (Box-folder 7:35)
- Free Voice of Greece n.d. (Box-folder 7:36)
- Friends Committee on National Legislation 1966-1967 (Box-folder 7:37)
- Friends of Jerusalem 1978 (Box-folder 7:38)
- Friends Peace Committee 1965 (Box-folder 7:39)
- Hopi Tribe 1974, n.d. (Box-folder 7:40)
- Howard Allen Enterprises, Inc. 1980 (Box-folder 7:41)
- Hungary 1980 (Box-folder 7:42)
- Indochina Resource Center 1971 (Box-folder 7:43)
- Industrial Workers of the World n.d. (Box-folder 8:1)
- Institute for International Studies n.d. (Box-folder 8:2)
- Institute for New Communications 1974 (Box-folder 8:3)
- Institute for Policy Studies n.d. (Box-folder 8:4)
- Interior Castle-Martha of Jesus 1981 (Box-folder 8:5)
- International Council of Christian Churches 1970 (Box-folder 8:6)
- Jewish Currents 1976 (Box-folder 8:7)
- Jewish Student Press Service 1974 (Box-folder 8:8)
- KTAO 1973, n.d. (Box-folder 8:9)
- Kalamazoo Nature Center 1970, n.d. (Box-folder 8:10)
- Language Research Center 1973-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 8:11)
- Liberation 1966 (Box-folder 8:12)
- Liberty Bell Publications n.d. (Box-folder 8:13)
- Little Free Press n.d. (Box 8:14)
- Los Siete de la Raza n.d. (Box-folder 8:15)
- Massachusetts Political Action for Peace n.d. (Box-folder 8:16)
- The Militant 1980 (Box-folder 8:17)
- Mohawk Nation-Akwesasne Notes n.d. (Box-folder 8:18)
- National Anti-Klan Network 1980 (Box-folder 8:19)
- National Citizens Committee Concerned About Deployment of the ABM 1969 (Box-folder 8:20)
- National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy 1966 (Box-folder 8:21)
- National Council of Churches-Corporate Information Center 1972-1973 (Box-folder 8:22)
- National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee 1979 (Box-folder 8:23)
- National Interreligious Service Board for Conscientious Objectors (NISBCO) 1975-1979 (Box-folder 8:24)
- National Lawyers Guild n.d. (Box-folder 8:25)
- National Religious Committee Opposing ABM n.d. (Box-folder 8:26)
- National Unity Campaign for John Anderson 1980 (Box-folder 8:27)
- The Navajos n.d. (Box-folder 8:28)
- New American Movement n.d. (Box-folder 8:29)
- New England Free Press 1971, n.d. (Box-folder 8:30)
- New Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam n.d. (Box-folder 8:31)
- New York Harrisburg Defense Committee n.d. (Box-folder 8:32)
- New York Workshop in Nonviolence 1966-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 8:33)
- October League (Marxist, Leninist) - The Call 1974-1975 (Box-folder 8:34)
- The Oklahoma Observer 1972-1974 (Box-folder 8:35)
- Operation America 1965 (Box-folder 8:36)
- PCS Publications 1970 (Box-folder 8:37)
- Peacemaker Movement n.d. (Box-folder 8:38)
- Pentagon Papers Fund-Ellsberg Defense Committee 1972 (Box-folder 8:39)
- People's Party II: Houston, Texas n.d. (Box-folder 8:40)
- People's Party Treaty 1971, n.d. (Box-folder 8:41)
- People's Press 1971-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 8:42)
- People's Street Union 1969, n.d. (Box-folder 8:43)
- The People's Will n.d. (Box-folder 8:44)
- People's Yellow Pages: Ithaca, New York 1974 (Box-folder 8:45)
- Percy Press, Letter from Mrs. Alfred Percy concerning the 1974 (Box-folder 8:46)
- Petal Paper n.d. (Box-folder 8:47)
- Philadelphia Free Press-Philadelphia Worker 1975 (Box-folder 8:48)
- Philadelphia Resistance 1969-1972, n.d. (Box-folder 8:49)
- Philadelphia Solidarity 1973 (Box-folder 8:50)
- Philadelphia War Tax Resistance 1971 (Box-folder 8:51)
- Physicians for Social Responsibility 1968-1971 (Box-folder 8:52)
- Pink Sheet on the Left 1979 (Box-folder 8:53)
- Plainfield [New Jersey] Joint Defense Committee 1970, n.d. (Box-folder 8:54)
- Planned Communities, Inc. 1966 (Box-folder 9:1)
- Planned Parenthood-World Population 1967-1970, n.d. (Box-folder 9:2)
- Polaroid Revolutionary Workers Movement 1971 (Box-folder 9:3)
- Promoting Enduring Peace, Inc. 1966-1979 (Box-folder 9:4)
- Provisional Revolutionary Government of the Republic of South Vietnam 1969-1971 (Box-folder 9:5)
- Radical America 1980 (Box-folder 9:6)
- Radical Organizing Committee 1968, n.d. (Box-folder 9:7)
- Radio Free People 1970-1974 (Box-folder 9:8)
- Radical Education Project: Organization Information and Literature Lists 1969-1972 (Box-folder 9:9)
- Radical Education Project: Pamphlets-American Capitalism and the Economy 1965-1969, n.d. (Box-folder 9:10)
- Radical Education Project: Pamphlets-Black Power Movements 1965-1969, n.d. (Box-folder 9:11)
- Radical Education Project: Pamphlets-China 1965-1967, n.d. (Box-folder 9:12)
- Radical Education Project: Pamphlets-Imperialism 1964-1966, n.d. (Box-folder 9:13)
- Radical Education Project: Pamphlets-Labor 1967-1969, n.d. (Box-folder 9:14)
- Radical Education Project: Pamphlets-Miscellaneous 1966-1967, n.d. (Box-folder 9:15)
- Radical Education Project: Pamphlets-Miscellaneous Radical Groups and Movements n.d. (Box-folder 9:16)
- Radical Education Project: Pamphlets-Poverty n.d. (Box-folder 9:17)
- Radical Education Project: Pamphlets-Radicalism 1965-1969, n.d (Box-folder 9:18)
- Radical Education Project: Pamphlets-Vietnam 1967-1970, n.d. (Box-folder 9:19)
- Radical Education Project: Pamphlets-Women's Movement 1969, n.d. (Box-folder 9:20)
- Radical Education Project: Pamphlets-Youth and Universities 1966-1969, n.d. (Box-folder 9:21)
- Rage 1971 (Folder 10:1)
- Raider's Club 1973-1974 (Box-folder 10:2)
- Rainbow People 1971 (Folder 10:3)
- Red Balloon Collective n.d. (Box-folder 10:4)
- Revolutionary Union n.d. (Folder 10:5)
- Richland County Citizen's Committee, Columbia, South Carolina n.d. (Box-folder 10:6)
- Richmond Council for Peace Education 1966 (Box-folder 10:7)
- Richmond Human Rights Coalition 1980 (Box-folder 10:8)
- Richmond Mobilization Committee (Box-folder 10:9)
- The Richmond Prisoners Solidarity Committee n.d. (Box-folder 10:10)
- Richmond Women's Center [1974] (Box-folder 10:11)
- Rising Free-London 1973 (Box-folder 10:12)
- Riverside Political Prisoners Defense Committee 1974, n.d. (Box-folder 10:13)
- Rogosin Films n.d. (Box-folder 10:14)
- Royal Commission on the Status of Women in Canada 1968 (Box-folder 10:15)
- Rutgers University 1970 (Box-folder 10:16)
- San Francisco Bay Area Labor Assembly For Peace n.d. (Box-folder 10:17)
- San Francisco Women for Peace 1979 (Box-folder 10:18)
- San Jose Community Tenants Union n.d. (Box-folder 10:19)
- San Quentin Six Defense Committee 1975 (Box-folder 10:20)
- Sanity Now! 1972-1973, n.d. (Box-folder 10:21)
- Santa Cruz Committee to Repeal the Draft 1971 (Box-folder 10:22)
- Sapphire 1973 (Box-folder 10:23)
- Saturday Review 1967 (Box-folder 10:24)